{
  "user": [
    {
      "email": "anmol123@gmail.com",
      "fname": "anmol",
      "lname": "chaure",
      "password": "anmol123",
      "role": "admin",
      "gender": "male",
      "contact": 9283567048,
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "email": "panchashil145@gmail.com",
      "fname": "panchashil",
      "lname": "wankhade",
      "password": "panchshil45",
      "role": "trainer",
      "gender": "male",
      "contact": 8735412345,
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "email": "sam24@gmail.com",
      "fname": "samruddhi",
      "lname": "vaidya",
      "password": "sam249",
      "role": "trainer",
      "gender": "female",
      "contact": "8976453213",
      "id": 3
    },
    {
      "email": "rushikakdeforever@gmail.com",
      "fname": "rushikesh",
      "lname": "kakde",
      "password": "rushi@26",
      "role": "admin",
      "gender": "male",
      "contact": "8007419586",
      "id": 7
    },
    {
      "email": "samadhan1234@gmail.com",
      "fname": "samadhan",
      "lname": "kakde",
      "password": "sa123456",
      "role": "trainer",
      "gender": "male",
      "contact": "984558990",
      "id": 8
    }
  ],
  "react": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
      "options": [
        "React",
        "React.js",
        "ReactJS",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which of the following are the advantages of React.js?",
      "options": [
        "React.js can increase the application's performance with Virtual DOM",
        "React.js is easy to integrate with other frameworks such as Angular, BackboneJS since it is only a view library",
        "React.js can render both on client and server side.",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above."
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a disadvantage of React.js?",
      "options": [
        "React.js has only a view layer. We have put your code for Ajax requests, events and so on.",
        "The library of React.js is pretty large",
        "The library of React.js is pretty large",
        "The learning curve can be steep in React.js"
      ],
      "answer": "C is the correct answer.The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write is an advantage of React.js."
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
      "options": [
        "Original DOM",
        "Virtual DOM",
        "Both A and B.",
        "None of the above."
      ],
      "answer": "B is the correct answer. Virtual DOM is used in React.js to increase performance."
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
      "options": [
        "Constructor",
        "Class",
        "Both A and B.",
        "Object"
      ],
      "answer": "B is the correct answer. A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, we use the keyword class."
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Using which of the following command can prevent default behaviour at in react?",
      "options": [
        "preventDefault()",
        "avoidDefault()",
        "revokeDefault()",
        "Non of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "preventDefault()"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Identify the command used to create a react app?.",
      "options": [
        "npm install create-react-app",
        "npm install -g create-react-app",
        "install -g create-react-app",
        "Non of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "npm install -g create-react-app"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": " Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
      "options": [
        "Create",
        "Inherits",
        "Extends",
        "This"
      ],
      "answer": "Extends"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "  What is a state in React?",
      "options": [
        "A permanent storage.",
        "Internal storage of the component.",
        "External storage of the component.",
        "None of the above."
      ],
      "answer": "Internal storage of the component."
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "What is the use of webpack command in React.js?",
      "options": [
        "The webpack command is used to transpile all the JavaScript down into one file.",
        "It runs React local development server.",
        "It is a module bundler.",
        "None of the above."
      ],
      "answer": "C is the correct answer. The webpack command is a module bundler."
    }
  ],
  "python": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What is the maximum possible length of an identifier?",
      "options": [
        "16",
        " 32",
        "64",
        "None of these above"
      ],
      "answer": "(d) None of these above"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": " Who developed the Python language?",
      "options": [
        "Zim Den",
        "Guido van Rossum",
        "Niene Stom",
        "Wick van Rossum"
      ],
      "answer": "(b) Guido van Rossum"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
      "options": [
        "Constructor",
        "Class",
        "Both A and B.",
        "Object"
      ],
      "answer": "B is the correct answer. A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, we use the keyword class."
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
      "options": [
        "Constructor",
        "Class",
        "Both A and B.",
        "Object"
      ],
      "answer": "B is the correct answer. A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, we use the keyword class."
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": " Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
      "options": [
        "//",
        "#",
        "!",
        "/*"
      ],
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
      "options": [
        "Function",
        "def",
        "Fun ",
        "define"
      ],
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which of the following functions can help us to find the version of python that we are currently working on?",
      "options": [
        "sys.version(1)",
        "sys.version(0)",
        "sys.version()",
        "sys.version"
      ],
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "What does pip stand for python??",
      "options": [
        "Pip Installs Python",
        "Pip Installs Packages",
        "Preferred Installer Program",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
      "options": [
        "factorial()",
        "print()",
        " seed()",
        "sqrt()"
      ],
      "answer": "b"
    }
  ],
  "php": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following statement is correct for AngularJS?",
      "options": [
        "AngularJS is an HTML framework",
        "AngularJS is a Java framework",
        "AngularJS is a JavaScript framework",
        "AngularJS is a SQL framework"
      ],
      "answer": " C is the correct option. AngularJS is a JavaScript framework."
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": " On which of the Architectural pattern AngularJS is based?",
      "options": [
        "Observer Pattern",
        "Decorator pattern",
        "MVC Architecture pattern",
        "MVVM Architectural pattern"
      ],
      "answer": "D is the correct option. AngularJS is based on MVVM Architectural pattern."
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "AngularJS is perfect for?",
      "options": [
        "SPAs",
        "MPAs",
        "DPAs",
        "CPAs"
      ],
      "answer": " A is the correct option. AngularJS is perfect for Single Page Applications (SPAs)."
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following directive is used to bind the application data to the HTML view in AngularJS?",
      "options": [
        "ng-app directive",
        "ng-model directive",
        "ng-bind directive",
        "ng-init directive"
      ],
      "answer": " C is the correct option. The ng-bind directive is used to bind the application data to the HTML view in the AngularJS application."
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
      "options": [
        "Constructor",
        "Class",
        "Both A and B.",
        "Object"
      ],
      "answer": "B is the correct answer. A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, we use the keyword class."
    }
  ],
  "vcodes": [
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 1,
      "Vcode": "7aqvnU"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 2,
      "Vcode": "SZa8Qm"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 3,
      "Vcode": "yUapUy"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 4,
      "Vcode": "SgLBmw"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 5,
      "Vcode": "TZkSCK"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 6,
      "Vcode": "rEOHy9"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 7,
      "Vcode": "gCoC7V"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 8,
      "Vcode": "M7ebg7"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 9,
      "Vcode": "vVOnxq"
    },
    {
      "status": true,
      "id": 10,
      "Vcode": "MnF9q8"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 11,
      "Vcode": "wU4NOp"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 12,
      "Vcode": "A2Qekk"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 13,
      "Vcode": "opyAs6"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 14,
      "Vcode": "IwHLmT"
    },
    {
      "status": false,
      "id": 15,
      "Vcode": "MaMkbt"
    }
  ],
  "StudentResult": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "StudentName": "ravindra patil",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 10,
      "Grade": "-",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "StudentName": "Mayuri kakde",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "C++",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 30,
      "Grade": "C",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "StudentName": "ravindra patil",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 10,
      "Grade": "-",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "StudentName": "Mayuri kakde",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "C++",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 30,
      "Grade": "C",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "StudentName": "ravindra patil",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 10,
      "Grade": "-",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "StudentName": "Mayuri kakde",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "C++",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 30,
      "Grade": "C",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "StudentName": "pawan jadhav",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 45,
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "StudentName": "ravindra patil",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 10,
      "Grade": "-",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "StudentName": "Mayuri kakde",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "C++",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 30,
      "Grade": "C",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "StudentName": "pawan jadhav",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 45,
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "StudentName": "ravindra patil",
      "Orgnization": "Hematite",
      "Branch": "Chandannagar",
      "ExamName": "React js",
      "TotalMark": 50,
      "ObtainedMark": 10,
      "Grade": "-",
      "Date": "26/06/2023"
    }
  ],
  "students": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "firstname": "anmol",
      "lastname": "chaware",
      "email": "anmol@gmail.com",
      "contact": "1234567891",
      "dob": "1993-12-12",
      "gender": "Male",
      "organization": "hematite"
    },
    {
      "firstname": "Vishakha",
      "lastname": "Mankar",
      "email": "vish24mankar@gmail.com",
      "contact": "9765223448",
      "dob": "2023-08-18",
      "gender": "Female",
      "organization": "Warje",
      "pnr": "",
      "branch": null,
      "id": 2
    }
  ],
  "exams": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "code": "R1",
      "examname": "ReactJs",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "code": "R2",
      "examname": "Phython",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "code": "R3",
      "examname": "Java",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "code": "R4",
      "examname": "Javascript",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "code": "R5",
      "examname": "PHP",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "code": "R6",
      "examname": "Angular",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "code": "R7",
      "examname": "Veu.js",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "code": "HI-15",
      "examname": "react",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "code": "HI-17",
      "examname": "vbg",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "code": "bvh",
      "examname": "vchg",
      "examstatus": "enable",
      "action": ""
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "code": "HI-17",
      "examname": "mdvnfvnfnv",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "code": "HI-20",
      "examname": "hdvvc",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "code": "HI-23",
      "examname": "Sass",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "code": "h12",
      "examname": "abc",
      "examstatus": "disable"
    }
  ]
}
